### Summary

Mobile developer with around 8 years of experience building clean and maintainable software for a wide range of businesses ranging from Augmented Reality to Financial Services. Possess a strong technical background with a Masters Degree in Computer Engineering from the University of Florida. Lots of experience working in agile teams and also some independently as the only developer. Currently looking for a challenging new role and some fun people to work with. I have been living in the Netherlands for more than 5 years now and can speak Dutch as well:)

# App Showcase

_	Moneyou Go	iOS / Android
•	Modern online mobile banking solution in NL and DE	March 2018 - December 2018
•	2dehands.be	iOS
	Largest Online Marketplace in Belgium	June 2016 - December 2017
•	Blippar	iOS
	Visual Object Recognition and Augmented Reality	June 2015 - May 2016
•	Layar	iOS
	World's first major Augmented Reality Platform	November 2014 - May 2016
•	Jumbo	iOS
	E-commerce app for Jumbo Supermarket	February 2014 - November 2014

# Recent Work Experience

### Rabobank (Financial Services)

Senior Mobile Engineer - Freelance

Utrecht, The Netherlands March 2019 - May 2019

- Briefly joined the native mobile team at Rabobank and helped them with their hybrid app releases.
- Helped in interviewing new iOS Candidates
- Contributed to discussions about Banking IT architecture

## Moneyou / ABN AMRO (Financial Services)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands March 2018 - December 2018

Senior Mobile Engineer - Freelance

- Part of mobile team doing iOS and Android feature development and releases

- Interview new iOS Candidates
- Won moneyou hackathon and successfully implemented suggested features in the app
- Part of team creating a new and compliant banking backend infrastructure with AWS Serverless Lambdas

## Markplaats / Ebay Inc. (Classifieds)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

Senior iOS Engineer - Freelance

June 2016 - December 2017

- Singlehandedly maintain the 2dehands.be App for Belgium serving millions of users
- Part of the ebay global mobile team building classified apps for 11 different countries for example Gumtree UK
- Setup all required processes such as Automated Testing, Continuous Integration, Crash Analysis etc.
- Successfully hired and trained replacement for the role before exit

# **Previous Work Experience**

Layar / Blippar (Augmented Reality)

Amsterdam, The Netherlands November 2014 - May 2016

Senior iOS Engineer

- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar App that makes millions of users see Augmented Reality
- Lead Developer for the iOS Layar SDK that help businesses make Augmented Reality solutions
- Part of the team building the Blippar App for visual search

# IceMobile Agency Senior iOS Engineer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

February 2014 - November 2014

- Senior developer in the iOS development team building apps for the leading supermarkets in the Netherlands such as Jumbo and Albert Heijn
- Gathering business requirements and coming up with efficient technical solutions to address them
- Automating user interface testing and setting up continuous integration

Ebuddy

iOS Developer

Amsterdam, The Netherlands

June 2013 - January 2014

- Working in the iOS development team building the messaging app XMS that had millions of users around the world and was a competitor to watsapp

# MicroStrategy Inc.

McLean,VA

Software Engineer

September 2010 - January 2012

- Worked on several iOS development projects for the clients of Microstrategy and helped automate various tasks. Also helped develop the microstrategy SDK. iOS was a pretty new technology at this point so this was some really good experience.

Citisync.com

Gainesville,FL

*iOS Developer* 

January 2010- July 2010

Singlehandedly built the citisync iOS Application. This was when iOS 3 was the latest version. Also
my first experience as an iOS Developer and it piqued my interest in the field

Bloomberg LP

New York, NY

Financial Software Development Intern

May 2009 - August 2009

- As an intern in the manhattan office, I helped out with a number of projects in the Global Trading team writing code in C++ and managing large mainframe supercomputers

### Education

### University of Florida

Gainesville,FL

Masters in Computer Engineering

August 2008 - August 2010

- CGPA: 3.6/4.0

### Skills

Languages: Swift, Objective C, C, C++, Python, Bash, Javascript, Java, Kotlin

**Technical Skills:** iOS, Android, TDD, Automated Testing, CI, fastlane, git, xcode, Security, Machine Learning, Restful API Design, AWS Serverless, Agile/Scrum, Estimation, Writing User Stories, Presentations

## Other Interests

Pilot Training, Salsa Dancing, Travel, Poker, Pool and Snooker